<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MATLAB on Sneha Shah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/techs/matlab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MATLAB on Sneha Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Sneha Shah</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 19:47:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/techs/matlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jaw Volume Calculation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/jaw-volume-calculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/jaw-volume-calculation/</guid>
      <description>Wrote a program that uses image processing techniques to identify the volume of a human jaw from a 3D medical scan. This is part of a dental research on volume expansion of a jaw after using arch expansion treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note Identifier</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/note-identifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/note-identifier/</guid>
      <description>Using signal processing techniques to create an application to generate a real time pointer of the note (wrt Hindustani classical nomenclature) a person is singing, and a similar identification for a recorded song.Current model generates a rough graph which is accurate only for notes held longer. Working on accuracy of the identification by using different window types and sizes.Long term aim is to create a mobile application that helps beginner singers identify the accuracy of the note they are currently singing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Piano Tuning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/tuning-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/tuning-project/</guid>
      <description>Piano tuning is known to be difficult because the stiffness of piano strings causes the tones produced to be inharmonic. Aural tuning is time consuming and requires the help of a professional. This motivates the question of whether this process can be automated. Attempts at automatic tuning are usually assessed by comparing the Railsback curve of the results with the curve of a professional tuner. In this paper we determine a simple and reliable rule for tuning the high tones of a piano with the help of a listening test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/college-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/college-projects/</guid>
      <description>Automatic Classification of Bird Calls Jan 2019 – May 2019 Project under Dr. Sarang C Dhongdi ■ Studied algorithms that use signal processing techniques to identify bird species from their calls or songs, and compared results with machine learning algorithms for the same. ■ This is a continuation of a project where classification was done using mel­frequency cepstral coefficients.
Voice Scrambler and Unscrambler Aug 2018 – Dec 2018 As Part of ’Digital Signal Processing’ Course ■ Designing a system that scrambles and unscrambles voice signal for safe, loss­less transmission.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
